fleetmatics.com 2017-10-06

# Privacy Policy - Fleetmatics

####  General Information

This Privacy Statement explains what types of information Fleetmatics Group PLC and its wholly-owned subsidiaries (“Fleetmatics,” “we,” or “us”) or our service providers may collect from or about visitors to, or users of, our websites or applications (“you”), and describes our practices for collecting, using, retaining, protecting, disclosing, and transferring such information. 

####  Scope

This Privacy Statement applies to personal information and other information collected and controlled by Fleetmatics or its service providers from or about you when you (i) access Fleetmatics’ websites, (ii) use Fleetmatics applications (including mobile applications), products or services (individually and collectively, the “Services”), or (iii) open and respond to our e-mails. For purposes of this Privacy Statement, “personal information” means information that can be used to personally identify you, such as your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, billing and transaction information, credit card or other financial information, contact preferences, and similar information.

####  Information We Collect as Data Controller

When expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about the Services offered by us, or by registering to use the Services, Fleetmatics requires you to provide us with personal contact information, such as name, company name, address, phone number, and email address. When purchasing the Services, Fleetmatics may require you to provide us with financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the number of employees within the organization that will be using the Services. Fleetmatics may also ask you to provide additional information, such as company fleet size, size of your field services staff, annual revenues, number of employees, or industry. 

We may also obtain information about you that we collect from sources such as at conferences, meetings and seminars. We also may collect information through chat rooms, blog posts, newsgroups, and social networking sites. The information you allow us to access on social networking sites varies by social networking site, and it is affected by the privacy settings you establish at such site. You can control and find out more about the privacy settings of your social networking site on the applicable social networking site directly. Our website and Services may include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button or a “share this” feature. Your use of these features may direct you to Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, +Google or other social networking sites, but we do not collect information when you click on these features. We may also collect information about you from your friends or associates who tell us you may be interested in our Services. 

In some of our geographic locations, and to the extent permitted by applicable laws, we may monitor or record your telephone conversations with us for quality control purposes, for purposes of training our employees and for our own protection. 

We may also collect any information that you provide to us in connection with the use of our Services. We acknowledge your ownership rights in the information that you provide. We also may collect information that is related to you but that does not personally identify you, such as your computer’s operating system, browser, and information regarding your use of and activities on our websites or applications. See also the section below on cookies and other electronic tools used for the collection of such information. We may collect vehicle information, such as location and speed, through your use of our vehicle tracking Services, which we use to provide Services to our clients and for our own purposes. We own the information we collect through our vehicle tracking device in its aggregate and anonymized form and we reserve the right to use such aggregate, anonymized information without restriction. 

####  Use of Information We Control

Fleetmatics may use information that we collect from or about you, including any personal information:to welcome you to our website or Services; to help you complete a transaction or in order to deliver information or Services requested by you; to bill you for Services you purchased; to provide ongoing service and support, including event-related communications with respect to our Services; to notify you about changes to our websites or applications, or any Services we offer or provide through them; to improve our websites, applications, and Services, including by developing data analytics and reports about your use of them; to contact you to complete surveys that we use for marketing or quality assurance purposes; to deliver or display tailored online advertisements that may interest you; to e-mail or otherwise send you marketing or other promotional information about Fleetmatics or others’ products or services that may interest you; to combat fraud or any other criminal activity; to fulfill any other purpose for which you provide the information; or in any other way we may describe when you provide the information; as otherwise required or permitted by law; or for any other purpose with your consent. 

####  Data We Process for Others

We also may collect personal information from our clients who use our Services, who may elect to provide personal information into the system in order to utilize the Services. We process this information on behalf of our clients and only for their use of the system. We do not use or disclose such personally identifiable information except to provide the Services and in accordance with the instructions of the client as data controller.

####  Collection of Information Using Cookies and Other Tools

Fleetmatics may collect and/or log your IP address, Internet domain name, the web browser and operating system used to access Fleetmatics websites or applications, the pages or files visited, the time spent in each page or file, and the time and date of each visit or use. Fleetmatics may collect this information automatically as you browse our websites or use our applications through the use of log files, web beacons, or other electronic tools.

####  Cookies

Fleetmatics may use cookies to automatically collect information about your use of our websites. A "cookie" is a text file that is sent from a Web server to your browser and stored on your computer's hard drive or mobile device. Thereafter, when you visit that website, a message is sent back to the web server by the browser accessing the website, and this information about your activities is stored in the cookie. Use of cookies allows Fleetmatics to provide a higher quality, more relevant, customer experience. The information collected in cookies (e.g., the web pages you visit on the website and navigation patterns, the date and time of your visit, the number of links you click within the site, the functions you use on the site, the databases you view and the searches you request on the site, the data you save on, or download from, the site, the websites you visited immediately before and after visiting the site, and when you open our e-mails or click on any of their links) is used and analyzed to improve our service to you and to personalize your web-browsing experience by providing Fleetmatics with a better understanding of your interests and requirements regarding our websites and applications. Use of cookies may also allow us to automate entry into password-protected portions of our website so that you will not need to re-enter your password each time you visit such website. Cookies alone do not personally identify you; they are designed to recognize your web browser. However, if you have provided us with personal information, such as through completion of a web form, cookies may be linked to your personal information, such as your e-mail address or password.

Fleetmatics uses cookies that are session-based and persistent-cookies. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer when you close your browser software or turn off your computer. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you close your browser or turn off your computer. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. For more information about how to manage cookies in your web browser, see [https://www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/). Please note that if you disable your web browser’s ability to accept cookies, you will not be able to navigate Fleetmatics websites, and you will not be able to successfully use the Services. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will place cookies when you log on to our websites.

The following sets out how Fleetmatics uses different categories of cookies and your options for managing cookies’ settings:

####  Type of Cookies

| 

####  Description

| 

####  Managing Settings  
  
---|---|---  
  
Strictly necessary cookies

| 

These cookies enable you to navigate our websites and use their features, such as accessing secure areas of the websites and using Fleetmatics’ Services. These cookies allow the Company to uniquely identify you when you are logged into the Services and to process your online transactions and requests.

If you have chosen to identify yourself to Fleetmatics, we use cookies containing encrypted information to allow us to uniquely identify you. Each time you log into the web site or the Services, a cookie containing an encrypted, unique identifier that is tied to your account is placed on your browser.  
| Because required cookies are essential to operate the Fleetmatics websites and the Services, there is no option to opt out of these cookies.   
  
Performance cookies

| 

Anonymous usage cookies or “performance cookies” are used to associate a random session identifier with the usage activity that occurred during that session. Usage activity may include things like what pages were visited, how long a page was viewed, what page links were clicked on the most. This information is useful to create an overall view of how the greater community of users is interacting with our products and services.

|  By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device. You may decline these cookies by modifying your browser settings, though this will prevent you from successfully using the Services.   
  
Functionality cookies

| 

These cookies allow Fleetmatics’ websites to remember choices you make (such as your username, language, or the region you are in) and provide enhanced, more personal features. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customize. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for, such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. These cookies may be anonymized and they cannot track your browsing activity on other website.

| 

By using our website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device. You may decline these cookies by modifying your browser settings, though this will prevent you from successfully using the Services.  
  
Targeting cookies or advertising cookies

| These cookies are used to deliver advertisements more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator’s permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organizations such as advertisers. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organization. 

Fleetmatics sometimes uses cookies delivered by third parties to track the performance of our advertisements. For example, these cookies remember which visitors have visited the Fleetmatics websites. The information provided to third parties does not include personal information, but this information may be re-associated with personal information after Fleetmatics receives it. 

We also contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information from web beacons (see below) on our websites, from emails, and on third-party websites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time by collecting information through the website through automated means, including through the use of cookies. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other websites. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.

|  To learn more about these and other advertising networks and their opt out instructions, click <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> or ****<https://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>.   

#### Web Beacons

When we send you emails, we may include a web beacon to allow us to determine the number of people who open our emails. Web beacons are transparent graphic images placed in emails or web pages to record the simple actions of users. For example, when you click on a link in an email, we may record your response to allow us to customize our offerings to you. Web beacons collect only limited information, such as time and date of a page being viewed, and a description of the page on which the web beacon resides (the URL). Web beacons can be refused when delivered via email. If you do not wish to allow web beacons via email, you may disable HTML images or refuse HTML (select Text only) within your email software.

####  IP Addresses

When you visit Fleetmatics’ websites, we collect your Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses to track and aggregate non-personal information. For example, we use IP addresses to monitor the regions from which customers and visitors navigate our websites.

####  Links

Fleetmatics’ websites may contain links to third-party websites, including our partners’ websites and others. If you access those links, you will leave the Fleetmatics website. Fleetmatics does not control these third-party websites or their privacy practices, which may differ from those of Fleetmatics. These websites are not governed by this Privacy Statement, and we do not take responsibility for the privacy practices of any third-party websites to which we link. We encourage you to review the privacy statement of any third-party entity to which we link before submitting your personal information.

####  Social Networking and Refer a Friend

We may use chat rooms, blog posts, newsgroups, and social networking sites in order to market to you by directing users of such chat rooms, blog posts, news groups and social networking sites to our website for more information. We may use such information to contact you for consent, but will not use your information or post without such consent. If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about a page on a Fleetmatics website, you will be asked to submit an email to your friend directly. Fleetmatics does not store this information, except to the extent permitted by law. If your friends refer you to us directly we may in certain geographical locations use the contact information provided in order to market to you, in accordance with applicable law.

####  Sharing and Usage of Your Personal Information

We are the sole owner of information collected on our websites, except for content that you provide to us in connection with your use of our Services. We collect information only as necessary to fulfill the purposes set forth in this Privacy Statement and we will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed here. Except as described in this Privacy Statement, Fleetmatics does not share, sell, rent, or trade any information with third parties for their promotional purposes. We may disclose information that does not identify any individual (e.g., anonymous, aggregated data) without restriction.

Fleetmatics contracts with third-party service providers and suppliers (including distributors and resellers) to deliver certain products, services, and customer solutions. Examples of such services provided on our behalf are mail delivery, website hosting, transaction processing, processing payments, sending emails on our behalf, providing you with support via live chat software, and event planning. Fleetmatics may share your personal information with its service providers and suppliers to the extent necessary to deliver the product or service you requested, respond to your requests for information on products or services, or otherwise support your business needs.

Third-party service providers and suppliers receiving personal information are expected to maintain privacy and security protections that are consistent with Fleetmatics’ privacy and information security policies. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only for the purpose for which it was originally intended or as required or permitted by law. 

Some Fleetmatics websites or services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such websites/services, both Fleetmatics and the other company may receive information collected in conjunction with the co-branded website/services.

We may also disclose your personal information and other information, including across country borders: to our subsidiaries, affiliates, and worldwide offices to process such information in accordance with this Privacy Statement; to comply with the law or in response to a subpoena, court order, law enforcement or government request, or other legal process; to produce relevant documents or information in connection with litigation, arbitration, mediation, adjudication, government or internal investigations, or other legal or administrative proceedings, if Fleetmatics determines in its good faith judgment that such disclosure is necessary to provide its services or to protect the rights, interests, safety, or property of its business, employees, suppliers, customers, or others; in connection with any proposed or actual sale or other transfer of some or all assets of Fleetmatics, and/or any proposed or actual sale or merger of Fleetmatics or any division of Fleetmatics; to enforce the terms of any agreement with Fleetmatics; to combat fraud or other criminal activity; for any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information; as otherwise required or permitted by law; and/or with your consent.

#### Transfer of Your Information to Other Countries and Compliance with the European Union’s Safe Harbor Framework

For users of the Services in the European Union (other than the UK) and Asia-Pacific regions, all personal data submitted through the Services will be controlled by Fleetmatics IRL Limited. For users of the Services in the United Kingdom, all personal data submitted through the Services will be controlled by Fleetmatics (UK) Ltd. For users of the Services in the United States, Canada and Latin America, all personal data will be controlled by Fleetmatics USA, LLC. In accordance with applicable law, personal and other information covered by this Privacy Statement may be transferred to, and processed and stored in, the European Union, the United States or any other country in which Fleetmatics or its affiliates, subsidiaries, service providers, business partners, or customers maintain facilities. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy, even when your information is processed in a country which permits a level of data privacy that is lower than that required by the European Union or under the Safe Harbor Framework. By submitting your personal information to Fleetmatics, you acknowledge that such information may be transferred to other countries.

Fleetmatics Group PLC complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

####  For Users in California

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by Fleetmatics to its affiliates and/or third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail with your first name, last name, mailing address, e-mail address, and telephone number to [legal@fleetmatics.com](mailto:legal@fleetmatics.com). Please include “California Privacy Rights” in the subject line of your e-mail.

####  Security

Fleetmatics has implemented reasonable administrative, technical, and physical measures designed to protect your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, disclosure, use, alteration, or destruction. When you provide us with credit card information via a Fleetmatics website, we will encrypt that information via SSL. If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Please also be careful to avoid “phishing” scams, where someone may send you an e-mail that looks like it is from Fleetmatics asking for your personal information. If you have questions regarding our security you can contact us via [legal@fleetmatics.com](mailto:legal@fleetmatics.com).

####  Children’s Online Information Policy

Fleetmatics understands the importance of protecting children's privacy, particularly with their online interactions. Fleetmatics websites are not designed for and do not intentionally target or solicit anyone younger than 13 years of age.

####  Access to and Correcting Your Information

If you receive marketing or similar e-mail messages from us and you wish to opt out of receiving such messages, you may follow the opt-out procedure specified in the e-mail message or you may contact [marketing@fleetmatics.com](mailto:marketing@fleetmatics.com). If after expressing an interest in our Services you wish no longer to receive marketing telephone calls from us, you can opt-out of receiving such marketing telephone calls by contacting [marketing@fleetmatics.com](mailto:marketing@fleetmatics.com). If you wish to update or modify your billing information, please contact [AR@fleetmatics.com](mailto:AR@fleetmatics.com). Customers of Fleetmatics Services are not able to opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their account with Fleetmatics or the Services.

If you wish to review or modify information submitted to us directly, you should contact [marketing@fleetmatics.com](mailto:marketing@fleetmatics.com). Within 30 days of your request, Fleetmatics will grant you reasonable access to personal information that it holds about you and take reasonable steps to permit you to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. We will take measures to verify your identity before providing you with, or updating, you information. You may also contact us by email at [legal@fleetmatics.com](mailto:legal@fleetmatics.com) or by regular mail at Fleetmatics, Attn: Legal Department, 1100 Winter Street, Waltham, MA 02451, USA.

For users of Services in the European Union, if we were unable to resolve your issue through one of the recourses above, you may contact the European Union Data Protection Authorities’ (“EU DPA”) Data Panel. The EU DPA’s Data Panel acts as an independent dispute resolution mechanism for disputes regarding the Safe Harbor Framework. For more information and to file a complaint, you may find a Data Panel complaint form at <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/document/international-transfers/adequacy/files/ussh/complaint_form_20130206_en.pdf>

#### Changes to this Privacy Statement

Fleetmatics will review and update this Privacy Statement periodically, and will note the date of its most recent revision above. If we make material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by prominently posting a notice of such changes on our websites or in the Services prior to implementing the changes. We encourage you to review this Privacy Statement frequently to stay informed about how Fleetmatics is collecting, using, retaining, protecting, disclosing, and transferring your information.

####  Contacting Us

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of Fleetmatics, please contact us at [legal@fleetmatics.com](mailto:legal@fleetmatics.com) or by regular mail to: Fleetmatics, Attn: Legal Department, 1100 Winter Street, Waltham, MA 02451, USA. 

Click here for Mobile Terms and Conditions / Privacy Statement.
